<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Journal</title>
    <link>http://mschauer.eu/journal/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Journal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 18:15:18 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://mschauer.eu/journal/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MicrostructureNoise</title>
      <link>http://mschauer.eu/journal/2018/05/17/microstructurenoise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 18:15:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mschauer.eu/journal/2018/05/17/microstructurenoise/</guid>
      <description>Introduction (Available as Jupyter notebook at https://github.com/mschauer/MicrostructureNoise.jl/blob/master/example/MicrostructureNoise.ipynb)
MicrostructureNoise is a Julia package for Bayesian volatility estimation in presence of market microstructure noise implementing the methodology described in our new preprint:
 Shota Gugushvili, Frank van der Meulen, Moritz Schauer, and Peter Spreij: Nonparametric Bayesian volatility learning under microstructure noise. arxiv:1805.05606, 2018.  This blogpost gives a short introduction.
Description MicrostructureNoise estimates the volatility function $s$ of the stochastic differential equation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mannheim Probability and Statistics Seminar: Continuous-discrete smoothing of diffusions</title>
      <link>http://mschauer.eu/journal/2018/05/09/mannheim-probability-and-statistics-seminar-continuous-discrete-smoothing-of-diffusions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 15:40:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mschauer.eu/journal/2018/05/09/mannheim-probability-and-statistics-seminar-continuous-discrete-smoothing-of-diffusions/</guid>
      <description>Presentation in the Mannheim Probability and Statistics Seminar. University of Mannheim. Wednesday, 2018-05-09, 12.15-13.00, room A5 C116.
Abstract Suppose X is a multidimensional diffusion taking values in ℝᵈ with drift b and dispersion coefficient σ, satisfying the stochastic differential equation (SDE)
dXₜ = b(t,Xₜ) dt + σ(t,Xₜ) dWₜ. (1)  The process W is a vector valued process consisting of independent Brownian motions. We assume the process is incompletely observed at times tᵢ and the n observations are given by</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seminar Marburg: Nonparametric Bayesian volatility estimation</title>
      <link>http://mschauer.eu/journal/2018/05/08/seminar-marburg-nonparametric-bayesian-volatility-estimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 15:41:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mschauer.eu/journal/2018/05/08/seminar-marburg-nonparametric-bayesian-volatility-estimation/</guid>
      <description>Presentation: Interdisziplinäres Statistik-Kolloquium der Universitäten Gießen und Marburg. Marburg, 2018-05-08, 18:15 Uhr im Hörsaalgebäude, Biegenstraße 14, Raum: HS 00/0070.
Abstract Given discrete time observations over a fixed time interval, we study a nonparametric Bayesian approach to estimation of the volatility coefficient of a stochastic differential equation. We postulate a histogram-type prior on the volatility with piecewise constant realisations on bins forming a partition of the time interval. The values on the bins are assigned an inverse Gamma Markov chain (IGMC) prior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multivariate stochastic differential equations with Bridge</title>
      <link>http://mschauer.eu/journal/2018/01/31/multivariate-stochastic-differential-equations-with-bridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mschauer.eu/journal/2018/01/31/multivariate-stochastic-differential-equations-with-bridge/</guid>
      <description>This IJulia script converted blog-post gives a tour for my package Bridge with focus on multivariate stochastic differential equations. I use Makie.jl for the visualisations. The notebook is online at https://github.com/mschauer/Bridge.jl/blob/master/example/3DExamples.ipynb .
Installation To run this IJulia script install Bridge and checkout the master branch to run.
# Pkg.add(&amp;#34;Bridge&amp;#34;) # Pkg.checkout(&amp;#34;Bridge&amp;#34;) The installation of Makie is a bit tricky and is detailed in the README.md file of Makie.
Setting the scene The next few lines load the needed packages and some scripts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parameter inference for a simple SIR model</title>
      <link>http://mschauer.eu/journal/2018/01/19/parameter-inference-for-a-simple-sir-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 18:20:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mschauer.eu/journal/2018/01/19/parameter-inference-for-a-simple-sir-model/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Mathieu Besançon made a nice blog post on Chris&amp;rsquo; DifferentialEquations ecosystem, https://mbesancon.github.io/post/2017-12-14-diffeq-julia/ .
The notebook is online at https://gist.github.com/mschauer/9da19ea563d072cb683aba80ab61efb4 .
One of the examples is simple model tracking individuals in a population with three states $S$, $I$, $R$.
Let $u = (u_1, u_2, u_2)$ be the vector of individuals in these states.
 At any moment an individual of state $A$ can convince a individual of state $B$ to join the fraction $A$ $$ S,I \mapsto 2I $$ This reaction happens proportional to the number of possible pairs $A, B$ which can match up, so proportional to $u_1 u_2$ with proportionality constant $\alpha$.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>